// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let questions = [
    {
    numb: 1,
    question: " In ordered linear search what are the best case and worst case complexity?",
    answer: "O(1),O(n)",
    options: [
      "O(nlogn), O(logn)",
      "O(logn), O(nlogn)",
      "O(n),O(1)",
      "O(1),O(n)"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "From the given statements which one is a disadvantage of linear search?",
    answer: "Greater time complexities compared to other searching algorithms",
    options: [
      "Requires more space",
      "Greater time complexities compared to other searching algorithms",
      "Not easy to understand",
      "Not easy to implement"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: " Speed difference execution of linear search(recursive) vs linear search(iterative)?",
    answer : "Linear search(iterative) is faster",
    options: [
      "Both execute at same speed",
      "Linear search(recursive) is faster",
      "Linear search(iterative) is faster",
      "Can't be said"
      ]
      
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "From the given following statements which one is not the application of binary search?",
    answer: "To search in an unordered list",
    options: [
      "To find the lower/upper bound in an ordered sequence",
      "Union of intervals",
      "Debugging",
      "To search in an unordered list"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "In bubble sort and selection sort the number of iterations in the given array is arr = {3,4,5,2,1} will be:",
    answer: "5 and 4",
    options: [
      "5 and 4",
      "4 and 5",
      "2 and 4",
      "2 and 5"
    ]
  },
   {
     numb: 6,
     question: "External sorting algorithm?",
     answer: "The algorithm that uses tape or disk during the sort",
     options: [
       "The algorithm that uses main memory during the sort",
       "The algorithm that uses tape or disk during the sort",
       "The algorithm that involves swapping",
       "The algorithm that is considered 'in place'"
     ]
   },
    {
     numb: 7,
     question: "Find the suitable modulo value for the given pattern of the length-5 window.Pattern is : 4 3 2 5 0",
     answer: "13",
     options: [
       "13",
       "14",
       "12",
       "11"
     ]
   },
   {
     numb: 8,
     question: "True regarding Euclid’s algorithm is that it calculates",
     answer: "GCD of two numbers",
     options: [
       "GCD of two numbers",
       "GCD of more than three numbers",
       "LCM of two numbers",
       "LCM of more than two numbers"
     ]
   },
  {
     numb: 9,
     question: "Choose the correct recurrence relation used in Strassen’s algorithm is:",
     answer: "7T(n/2) + Theta(n^2)",
     options: [
       "7T(n/2) + Theta(n^2)",
       "8T(n/2) + Theta(n^2)",
       "7T(n/2) + 0(n^ 2)",
       "8T(n/2) + 0(n^2)"
     ]
   },
   {
     numb: 10,
     question: "correct formula to generate random numbers between range(lower, upper) using rand() function:",
     answer: "(rand()%(upper-lower+ 1)) + lower",
     options: [
       "rand() % (upper - lower)",
       "rand() + lower",
       "(rand()%(upper-lower)) + lower",
       "(rand()%(upper-lower+ 1)) + lower"
     ]
   },
];